RALPH LAURENCE GARCIA VISAYA

Blk 2 Lot 2 Alexandra South Subd, Majada Labas

Calamba City, Laguna, Philippines, 4027

Mobile No: 59537693039

Email address: arelvisaya@gmail.com



OBJECTIVE:

To be part of an organization and institution where I get ample opportunities to explore and enhance my skills to the fullest and practice what I have learned preferably in the field of Electronics Engineering or any related work that will suit my qualifications, thereby contributing to the growth of organization. And to attain high advantage and privilege of learning experiences and abilities that entails personal improvement and development.

PERSONAL DATA:

Date of Birth:

November 3, 1992

Place of Birth:

Los Baños, Laguna

 Sex
 Male

 Age:
 31

 Height:
 5'3.2"

 Weight:
 49 kg.

Religion Born Again Christian

Nationality: Filipino

Language Spoken Filipino, English

Civil Status: Married

Father's Name Romualdo Visaya
Occupation Factory Worker
Mother's Name Winna Visaya

Occupation None

EDUCATIONAL ATTAINMENT:

Graduate SY 2018 – Present Master of Science in Electronics Engineering

Batangas State University – Alangilan Campus

Alangilan, Batangas City

Tertiary: SY 2012 - 2016 Bachelor of Science in Electronics and

Communications Engineering

Lyceum of the Philippines University – Laguna

Makiling, Calamba City

SY 2010 - 2012 Bachelor of Science in Electronics and

Communications Engineering

Polytechnic University of the Philippines

Sto. Tomas Batangas Campus

Secondary: SY 2006 - SY 2010 Rizal Institute - Canlubang

Salutatorian

Canlubang, Calamba City

Primary: SY 2000 - SY 2006 Canlubang Elementary School

First Honorable Mention Canlubang, Calamba City

QUALIFICATIONS AND SKILLS:

Computer literate

Good moral and communication skills

Inherent initiative and work ethics

Fast learner and willing to work under pressure

Knowledgeable in Electronics and Communications and other fields related to General

Engineering and Applied Sciences and Mathematics

Knowledgeable in C/C++ Programming, MATLAB, AutoCAD, EagleCAD, Multisim, Arduino

Programming especially in Mechatronics and Robotics, Verilog/VHDL Programming, IC and PCB

Design, PLC Programming and Networking, Fuzzy Logic, Neural Network, Android Studio, Android

Programming, Python Programming Language, CCTV, Access Control, Biometrics Site Survey,

Installation, Configuration, Testing and Commissioning

Conversant in English and Filipino

OJT EXPERIENCE:

RCA Computer and Services

Technician

Barangay Real, Crossing Calamba, City

Job Description: Configure basic computer hardware and software, computer maintenance and troubleshooting

Job Date: October 2010- November 2010

Ionics EMS Inc.

Test Support Group/Engineer Plant 5

Circuit Street, Light Industry and Science Park of the Philippines I.

Cabuvao, 4025 Laguna

Job Description: Support for the failure analysis of the PCB, Preventive maintenance of the ATE Machines,

Cabling, PCB failure analysis Job Date: March 2014- May 2014

JOB EXPERIENCE:

PrulifeUK

Licensed Financial Advisor

10th Flr. Ayala North Exchange, Ayala Ave

Job Description: Customer support, prepare meetings and sales for the prospects and clients

Job Date: June 2020- June 2021

Tanauan City College

Part TimeCollege Instructor

Trapiche, Tanauan Batangas

Job Description: Prepare lessons and modules for the online class especially the computer engineering students. Handled Electronics and Data analysis subjects, Microcontrollers, Signals and Programming

Job Date: Feb 3, 2020 - January 31, 2024

Mustard Seed Systems Corporation

Technical Support Engineer / RMA Engineer

47 Kamias Rd, Brgy Pinyahan, Quezon City

Job Description: Installation, troubleshooting, site visit and support for CCTV, Biometrics, FDAS, and different security devices handled by the company. Prepare for technical demo of the devices for the clients and different companies inside and outside NCR. Prepare technical reports per month and preventive maintenance.

Job Date: September, 2018 – November 2019

STI College - Calamba

Faculty Member IT Department/Computer Engineering Adviser

Brgy. Uno, Calamba City, Laguna

Job Description: Prepare lessons and modules for the especially the computer engineering students. Handled programming classes like C#, C++, Networks, Signals , Data Communications and mathematics Job Date: June 2017 – May 2018

Chemistry Laboratory Technician/Assistant Lecturer/Instructor

Km 54. Barangay Makiling, Calamba City, Laguna

Job Description: Handled chemistry laboratory equipment, teach programming basics in embedded model.

Job Date: June 2016 - June 2017

AFFILIATION:

Member Organization of Electronics and Communications Engineering Students-

PUP (OECES) June 2010 - 2012

Member Institute of Electronics and Communications Engineers of the Philippines

(IECEP-CALABARZON)

June 2010 - 2012

Member Institute of Electronics and Communications Engineers of the Philippines

(IECEP-LAGUNA)
June 2012 - Present

Instrumentalist Lyceum Concert Singers

January 31 2014 - May 31 2015

Vice-President Reflectors LPU-L
External June 2015 - March 2016

President Mechatronics and Robotics Society of the Philippines LPU-L Chapter

June 2015 - March 2016

Adviser Organization of Computer Engineering Students STI Calamba Campus

June 2017 - May 2018

SEMINARS ATTENDED:

August 2013 Fiber-to-the Home Technology

University of Perpetual Help System Calamba

Jose M, Francia, ECE

July 2014 Microelectronics Revolution: The Philippine Roadmap

Colegio de San Juan de Letran Calamba, Laguna

Robert de Luna, PECE

July 2014 Audio Engineering and ECE Roadmap of the Philippines

Colegio de San Juan de Letran Calamba

Joel B. Bajador, PECE

September 18, 2014 ASEAN Chartered Professional Engineer Registry (ACPER)

Lyceum of the Philippines University-Laguna

March 4, 2015 Industrial Robotics and Biomedical Engineering

Lyceum of the Philippines University-Laguna

March 20, 2015 Introduction to Digital Image Processing Using MATLAB

Lyceum of the Philippines University-Laguna

Engr. John William F. Orillo

July 27, 2015 Introduction to Mechatronics and Robotics with Green Technology

Polytechnic University of the Philippines- Sto Tomas Branch

Engr. Luis Bartolo

June 1, 2017 Zuken Launching E3 Series and CADSTAR in Partnership with

CIMTECHNOLOGY

Monet Hall, Crimson Hotel, Alabang, Muntinlupa City

April 13,2019 Graduate School Multidisciplinary Research Forum

Batangas State University Main Campus

May 4,2019 First Engineering Graduate School Research Forum "Propelling Engineers

Towards Excellence Through Research"
Batangas State University – Alangilan Campus

RESEARCH ENDEAVORS:

February 2015 Design and Simulation Fan Speed Control System Using Arduino

Microcontroller

Presented in The Research and Educational Development Training Institute Conference at Hotel Supreme Convention Plaza in Baguio City.

March 8, 2015 **Design and Development of Fuzzy Logic Algorithm with Varying Set Points**

For Fan Speed Control System Using Arduino Microcontroller

Presented in De La Salle University ResCon 2016 with Submission No.

71 (Published)

March 8, 2015 Development of Digital Regulated DC Power Supply with Auto Polarity

Corrector using Arduino Microcontroller

Presented in De La Salle University ResCon 2016 with Submission No.

69 (Published)

October 21, 2016 Design, Development and Implementation of a PID Tuning with Fuzzy

Logic Based Flight Controller and Smoothing Technique of an Unmanned

Aerial Vehicle (Quadcopter) Using Arduino Microcontroller

Presented in 2nd LPU-L Research Colloquium – RCCEA 2016

November 24, 2016 Development of Digital Regulated DC Power Supply with Auto Polarity

Corrector using Arduino Microcontroller

Presented in Pearlmont Hotel Cagayan De Oro City, Philippines in CAITE

ICPEP National Conference

June 20, 2017 Design and Development of a Fuzzy Logic Based - Digital Regulated DC

Power Supply with an Automatic Reverse Polarity Using Arduino

Microcontroller

Presented in the DLSU Research Congress 2017

SEMINARS SPEAKER:

August 11, 2017 Integrated Circuit Design and Verification: An Introduction to Field

Programmable Gate Array (FPGA) with XLINX ISE and Verilog/VHDL

Programming Language

July 28, 2017 Introduction to Arduino Microcontroller and Basic Programming

July 28, 2017 Introduction to Mechatronics and Robotics: Leading to Mechatronics NCII

September 9, 2017 Integrated Circuit Design and Verification: Xilinx ISE and Verilog/VHDL

Programming Workshop

August 18, 2020 Security Solutions: The Emerging and Empowerment of Technologies,

Its Application thru Hardware and Software

November 29, 2022 Introduction to Mobile Application

December 7, 2023 TechConnect 2023: Bridging Academia to Industry

CHARACTER REFERENCES:

John Michael Santos Customer Support-Supervisor Mustard Seed Systems Corporation

Jimver Diwa Professional Trader Forex

Engr. Rionel Belen Caldo Senior Model-Based Design Engineer Rohm LSI Design Philippines

I hereby certify that the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

RALPH LAURENCE G. VISAY